Guide to the J. M. Barrie Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1686–1955; Series I; 8.13; 20 boxes
  - Letters from J. M. Barrie
    - Motoring (to the editor), 1903 May 8 (Box 12, Folder 383)
      Declining an offer to be photographed.
    - Moult, Thomas, 1923–1929 (Box 12, Folder 384)
      Concerning Moult's article and book about Barrie.
    - "Moynihan", 1930 December 17 (Box 12, Folder 385)
    - Mozley, E., 1903 February 7 (Box 12, Folder 386)
      Endorsed by E. Mozley with note to "Cooper" arranging cricket matches.
    - Muir, William, 1929 (Box 12, Folder 387)
      Accompanied by a draft from Muir to Barrie dated October 7, [1929].
    - Muirhead, Dr., 1923 May 10 (Box 12, Folder 388)
    - Muirhead, James F. (James Fullarton), 1932 February 7 (Box 12, Folder 389)
    - Murray, David Christie and Sophie, 1893; 1906 (Box 12, Folder 390)
      The 1893 letter is published in Letters of J. M. Barrie, edited by Viola Meynell (New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1947).
    - Murray, Gilbert, 1907; 1917 (Box 12, Folder 391)
      The 1907 letter concerns the fight by literary and theatrical people against government censorship of stage productions.
    - Murray, Mr., 1905 December 21 (Box 12, Folder 392)
      Published in Letters of J. M. Barrie, edited by Viola Meynell (New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1947).
    - National Observer (to the editor), undated (Box 12, Folder 393)
    - National Press Agency, Ltd., 1897 October 31 (Box 12, Folder 394)
    - Nevinson, Margaret Wynne, 1918 January 18 (Box 12, Folder 395)
    - Newbigging, William, 1907 (Box 12, Folder 396)
    - Newbolt, Francis, 1925 (Box 12, Folder 397)
    - Newman, George, 1926 July 11 (Box 12, Folder 398)
    - Newton, Charles, undated (Box 12, Folder 399)
    - Nicoll, W. Robertson (William Robertson), 1890–1923 (Box 12, Folder 400)
      One letter accompanied by an autograph letter, signed, from Thomas James Wise to "Uncle Ernest" explaining the letter.
    - Noble, Edward, undated (Box 12, Folder 401)
    - Norman, Henry, 1902 November 27 (Box 12, Folder 402)
    - Norris, W. Foxley (William Foxley), 1928 (Box 12, Folder 403)
    - O'Grady, Mrs., 1917 November 2 (Box 13, Folder 404)
    - Oliphant, Mrs., 1888; 1889 (Box 13, Folder 405)
    - Oliver, John, 1900 April 11 (Box 13, Folder 406)
    - Ollivant, Mrs., undated (Box 13, Folder 407)
    - Osborne, Charles C. (Charles Churchill), 1912 September 22 (Box 13, Folder 408)
      Expressing interest in "Bob Stevenson's boy."
    - Owen, Rebekah, 1893 October 1 (Box 13, Folder 409)
      Regarding a copy of his A Window in Thrums, 11th ed. (London, 1893) to be sent to Thomas Hardy. Removed from a copy of the above edition.
    - "Lady Oxford", 1925; 1932 (Box 13, Folder 410)
    - Paget, R. M., 1908 October 24 (Box 13, Folder 411)
    - "Pain", undated (Box 13, Folder 412)
    - Parker, Louis Napoleon, 1898 November 9 (Box 13, Folder 413)
    - Parrott, Edward, 1906 March 30 (Box 13, Folder 414)
    - Partridge, Bernard, 1891–1900 (Box 13, Folder 415-416)
      Seventeen letters to Partridge, some concerning Barrie's play Richard Savage, H. B. Marriott Watson, and Partridge's illustrations for The Works of J. M. Barrie (New York, 1896); bound in blue leather. Accompanied by a précis of the letters (1946).
    - Payne, Ben Iden, 1911–1913 (Box 13, Folder 417)
    - Pearsall, Mrs., 1921–1922 (Box 13, Folder 418)
      Accompanied by photograph of Michael Llewelyn Davies.
    - Pentland, Nicol, 1892; 1897 (Box 13, Folder 419)
    - Perry, Denis L., 1918 (Box 13, Folder 420)
    - Phelps, Ruth Shepard, 1901 November 2 (Box 13, Folder 421)
      Concerning a tea party at Smith College.
    - "Phil", undated (Box 13, Folder 422)
      Concerning serving on a committee.
    - Phillpotts, Eden, 1897–1915 (Box 13, Folder 423)
      Discussing Phillpotts' literary work.
    - Piggott, William Charter, 1898 September 15 (Box 13, Folder 424)
    - Pinero, Arthur Wing, 1903?-1933 (Box 13, Folder 425)
    - Pinero, Myra, 1908 September 5 (Box 13, Folder 426)
    - Plymouth, Lord, 1912 October 18 (Box 13, Folder 427)
      Concerning a dinner for Sir Sydney Colvin.
    - Pol, Mrs., undated (Box 13, Folder 428)
    - Pole, Katharine, 1917–1932; undated (Box 13, Folder 429)
    - Ponsonby, J. T. Woolryd, 1936 February 5 (Box 13, Folder 430)
    - Ponsonby, Magdalen, 1908–1928 (Box 13, Folder 431)
      Including one letter granting permission for a performance in France of The Old Lady Shows Her Medals, and one addressed to "Ponsonby." Accompanied by an article on Barrie by Granville Barker, clipped from The Bookman (October 1910).
    - Pound, James B., 1896 July 14 (Box 13, Folder 432)
    - Press Association (Great Britain), 1922–1926 (Box 13, Folder 433)
      Two-way correspondence with the association's director H. C. Robbins; enclosures include a typescript carbon copy of Barrie's commencement address at the University of St Andrews (April 1922), a press clipping of Barrie's address at Wallasey High School (February 1924), and an autograph manuscript, signed, of "Cast Adrift," Barrie's address at Freedom of Dumfries (December 1924).
    - Preston, James Rudge, 1917 May 16 (Box 13, Folder 434)
    - Preston, Mrs., 1883 March 9 (Box 13, Folder 435)
    - Price, Nancy, 1901–1907 (Box 13, Folder 436)
    - Queen, William, 1927 May 21 (Box 13, Folder 437)
      Advising Queen to send his plays to R. Golding Bright.
    - R. R. Clark (Firm), 1895 April 7 (Box 13, Folder 438)
      Concerning the proofs for the Auld Licht Idylls.
    - Read, John, 1934; 1936 (Box 13, Folder 439)
    - Redgrave, Michael, 1917 February 26 (Box 13, Folder 440)
    - Reece, Mrs., 1911 April 19 (Box 13, Folder 441)
      Concerning the return of her manuscripts.
    - Reed, Edward Tennyson, 1897–1901 (Box 13, Folder 442)
      Includes photograph of Barrie and some members of the Allahakbarries Cricket Club: Walter Frith, William Meredith, G. Gilmour, Owen Seaman, Charles Tennyson, Henry Justice Ford, W. Hooper, G. Cotterill, Alfred Edward Woodley Mason, and Augustin Birrell.
    - Rees, Alec L., 1934 August 2 (Box 13, Folder 443)
    - Rees, Wilkins, 1898–1922 (Box 13, Folder 444)
    - Reid, T. Wemyss (Thomas Wemyss), 1890–1903 (Box 14, Folder 445)
    - Rhodes Trust (Oxford, England), 1929 February 26 (Box 14, Folder 446)
    - Richmond, Oliffe, 1932 (Box 14, Folder 447)
    - Rickett, Arthur, 1905 January 12 (Box 14, Folder 448)
      Declining an offer of the presidency of the Fairy Tale Society.
    - Riding, William H., 1893 (Box 14, Folder 449)
      Agreeing to write for the Youth's Companion.
    - Rigby, Mrs., 1922 May 18 (Box 14, Folder 450)
    - Ristori, Adelaide, 1886 July 16 (Box 14, Folder 451)
    - Ritchie, Anne Thackeray, 1896–1919 (Box 14, Folder 452)
      The 1897 letter also includes an undated note (probably in the hand of Lady Ritchie) to an unidentified recipient. The 1899 letter expresses Barrie's opinion of The Autobiography and Letters of Mrs. M. O. W. Oliphant.
    - Roberts, Kilham, 1932–1934 (Box 14, Folder 453)
    - Robins, Miss, 1891 April 23 (Box 14, Folder 454)
    - Robinson, J. Armitage (Joseph Armitage), 1909 May 19 (Box 14, Folder 455)
      Draft in the name of the Royal Literary Fund to the Dean of Westminster Abbey, London, containing a request for the burial of George Meredith in the Abbey. Inscribed by Edmund Gosse: "Handed across the table to me by J.M.B." Accompanied by an autograph manuscript note regarding the burial of George Meredith.
    - Rook, Mr., 1896 September 26 (Box 14, Folder 456)
      Congratulating Rook on his short story about "the two soldiers & a woman."
    - "Rose", 1901 January 22 (Box 14, Folder 457)
    - Rowley, Alfred, 1903–1909 (Box 14, Folder 458)
      Concerning a Peter Pan medal and a Peter Pan cup given by Barrie as prizes at the annual Christmas competition of the Serpentine Swimming Club.
    - Royal Institute of British Architects, 1931 May 19 (Box 14, Folder 459)
    - Scott, Clement and Constance, 1891–1919 (Box 14, Folder 460)
      One letter mentions a German translation of Barrie's play Ibsen's Ghost.
    - Scribner, Mrs., 1928 (Box 14, Folder 461)
    - Sedgwick, S. N. (Sidney Newman), 1915 January 12 (Box 14, Folder 462)
      Concerning a play written by Sedgwick.
    - Shaw, Bernard, 1907 November 20 (Box 14, Folder 463)
      Presenting Barrie's point of view on stage censorship.
    - Shearme, Angela, 1920 March 31 (Box 14, Folder 464)
    - Sheppard, Mrs., 1916 January 16 (Box 14, Folder 465)
    - Shiel, M. P. (Matthew Phipps), 1934–1935 (Box 14, Folder 466)
      Concerning a Civil List Pension for Shiel. Accompanied by other letters concerning Shiel's application, written to or from John Buchan, John Gawsworth, and the Civil List Pension Fund Trustees.
    - Shield, Katharine, 1927 (Box 14, Folder 467)
      Photocopies of letters, one from Shield to Barrie and his reply, in the Guilford College Library. They may not be reproduced.
      Gift of Guilford College Library, 1981.
    - Shorter, Clement King, 1904–1925 (Box 14, Folder 468)
    - Sichel, Edith Helen, 1904; 1911 (Box 14, Folder 469)
    - Sichel, Walter and Constance, 1913–1923 (Box 14, Folder 470)
    - Sidgwick Jackson, 1926 September 7 (Box 14, Folder 471)
      Concerning their map of "Fairyland."
    - Silver, Christine, 1920 July 7 (Box 14, Folder 472)
    - Simpson, Henry, 1921 January 2 (Box 14, Folder 473)
      Concerning a dinner of the Poets' Club.
    - Simson, Lady, 1927 January 11 (Box 14, Folder 474)
    - Sinclair, Mr., 1936 July 21 (Box 14, Folder 475)
    - Sitwell, Mrs., undated (Box 14, Folder 476)
    - Smellie, Mr., 1898 January 29 (Box 14, Folder 477)
    - Smith, Herbert Greenhough, 1913 October 6 (Box 14, Folder 478)
    - Smith, Mary Bentinck, undated (Box 14, Folder 479)
    - Smith, Miss, 1896 October 5 (Box 14, Folder 480)
    - Spence, Edward Fordham, 1913 June 22 (Box 14, Folder 481)
    - "Spender", 1907 January 3 (Box 14, Folder 482)
    - Spielmann, M. H. (Marion Harry), 1921 September 30 (Box 14, Folder 483)
      Concerning Hugh Thomson and illustrations for Quality Street.
    - Squire, John Collings, 1915; 1919 (Box 14, Folder 484)
      Concerning fishing and the Stevenson memorial in St. Giles Cathedral, Edinburgh.
    - Steel, Flora Annie Webster, 1907 January 4 (Box 14, Folder 485)
    - "Stephen", 1930 July 11 (Box 14, Folder 486)
      Gift of Henry C. Taylor (Yale 1917), 1952.
    - Stewart, Colville, 1915 August 31 (Box 14, Folder 487)
    - Stevenson, Fanny Van de Grift, 1896 December 3 (Box 14, Folder 488)
    - Stoker, Bram, 1892; 1907 (Box 14, Folder 489)
      Letter of 1907 published in Letters of J. M. Barrie, edited by Viola Meynell (New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1947).
    - Stoll, Oswald, undated (Box 14, Folder 490)
    - Storr, Vernon F. (Vernon Faithfull), 1935 July 26 (Box 14, Folder 491)
    - Strachey, Mrs., 1932 March 23 (Box 14, Folder 492)
    - Strong, Austin and Mary Holbrook Wilson, 1907–1919 (Box 14, Folder 493)
    - Sutton, Mr., 1925 September 4 (Box 14, Folder 494)
    - Sutton, Mrs., 1900 October 5 (Box 14, Folder 495)
    - Swan Sonnenschein Co., 1890 (Box 14, Folder 496)
    - Tearle, Godfrey, 1923 May 23 (Box 15, Folder 497)
    - Terry, Marion, 1906; 1921 (Box 15, Folder 498)
      Letter of March 5, 1906, gift of Mrs. Thomas N. Kendler Jr., 1937.
    - Thompson, Mr., 1925 July 14 (Box 15, Folder 499)
    - Thomson, David, 1913 July 6 (Box 15, Folder 500)
    - Thomson, Mr., 1896 March 10 (Box 15, Folder 501)
    - Thorndike, Sybil, Dame, 1927 November 28 (Box 15, Folder 502)
    - Thorpe, Rose Hartwick, undated (Box 15, Folder 503)
    - Thring, George Herbert, 1911 September 16 (Box 15, Folder 504)
    - Throne (to the editor), 1907 January 14 (Box 15, Folder 505)
    - Tomson, Mrs., 1893 December 6 (Box 15, Folder 506)
    - Tooley, Mrs., 1927 July 10 (Box 15, Folder 507)
    - Trevelyan, Hilda, 1902–1936 (Box 15, Folder 508-509)
      Forty-eight letters; some signatures have been cut out.
    - Trevelyan, George Macaulay, 1927 July 20 (Box 15, Folder 510)
    - Tweedie, Mrs., 1899–1909 (Box 15, Folder 511)
    - Vachell, Horace Annesley, 1932 November 30 (Box 15, Folder 512)
    - Vanbrugh, Irene, 1892–1936 (Box 15, Folder 513)
    - Vedrenne, John Eugene, 1906–1923 (Box 15, Folder 514)
      Some letters concerning the 1923 revival of What Every Woman Knows.
    - Vibart, Henry Meredith, 1902–1925 (Box 15, Folder 515)
    - "Violet", 1905 June 21 (Box 15, Folder 516)
    - Wakefield, Charles Cheers Wakefield, 1927–1930 (Box 15, Folder 517)
    - Walbrook, H. M. (Henry Mackinnon), 1903 October 19 (Box 15, Folder 518)
    - Walkley, Arthur Bingham, 1922 May 29 (Box 15, Folder 519)
      Enclosure wanting: Barrie's Rectorial address delivered at the University of St Andrews on May 3, 1922.
    - Wallace, Mr., 1894; 1906 (Box 15, Folder 520)
    - Ward, Humphry, Mrs., 1898–1907 (Box 15, Folder 521)
      Some letters concerning the dramatization of Mrs. Ward's Eleanor, contributions to her Vacation School, and the stage censorship controversy of 1907. One letter is also signed by John Galsworthy and Gilbert Murray.
    - Wason, Sandys, 1918 January 26 (Box 15, Folder 522)
    - Waters, James, 1910–1919 (Box 15, Folder 523)
    - Watson, Frederick, 1904–1917 (Box 15, Folder 524)
    - Watson, H. B. Marriott (Henry Brereton Marriott), 1887–1919 (Box 15, Folder 525-528)
      Some letters containing references to Barrie's earliest plays, Richard Savage and Walker, London, and to the cricket matches organized by Barrie for his friends.
    - Watson, Malcolm, 1899–1926 (Box 15, Folder 529)
    - Watson, Rosamund Marriott, 1905 May 10 (Box 15, Folder 530)
    - Watson, Miss (Box 15, Folder 531)
    - Waugh, Arthur, 1895 June 9 (Box 16, Folder 532)
    - "Weigle", 1902 December 22 (Box 16, Folder 533)
    - Welch, Mr., 1898 July 12 (Box 16, Folder 534)
    - Wellesley, Mrs., 1913 (Box 16, Folder 535)
    - Wheeler, Frederick, 1904 March 14 (Box 16, Folder 536)
    - Wheeler, Miss, 1913 January 15 (Box 16, Folder 537)
    - Wheeler, Mrs., 1907 November 9 (Box 16, Folder 538)
    - "Whelan", 1905 March 9 (Box 16, Folder 539)
    - White, Enid, 1928 (Box 16, Folder 540)
      Regarding the first manuscript copy of Barrie's play Peter Pan.
    - White, Miss, undated (Box 16, Folder 541)
    - Whitehouse, T. Howard, 1903 June 3 (Box 16, Folder 542)
    - Whitley, J. H. (John Henry), 1924 November 30 (Box 16, Folder 543)
    - Whitworth, Mr., 1927 February 6 (Box 16, Folder 544)
    - Whyte, Frederic, 1927 May 31 (Box 16, Folder 545)
      Concerning Whyte's William Heinemann: a Memoir, and mentioning Robert Louis Stevenson's connection with Heinemann.
    - Willard, E. S. (Edward Smith), 1906 December 5 (Box 16, Folder 546)
      Acknowledging royalty payment for A Professor's Love Story.
    - Williams, Bransby, undated (Box 16, Folder 547)
    - Williams, Lady, 1930 May 21 (Box 16, Folder 548)
    - Williamson, Mr., 1894 July 3 (Box 16, Folder 549)
    - Williamson, Mrs., 1891–1909 (Box 16, Folder 550)
    - Wilmot, Miss, 1897; 1899 (Box 16, Folder 551)
      Concerning poems written by Miss Wilmot and giving permission to her to paint a miniature of Barrie. Accompanied by an autograph letter, signed, to Miss Wilmot from J. Morris dated April 22, 1897.
    - Wilson, Charles, 1925 June 7 (Box 16, Folder 552)
    - Windsor Magazine (to the editor), 1894 March 4 (Box 16, Folder 553)
    - Winter, Helen, 1935 September 27 (Box 16, Folder 554)
    - Winter, Molly, 1934 December 20 (Box 16, Folder 555)
    - Winter, William, 1895 October 8 (Box 16, Folder 556)
    - Wotton, Miss, undated (Box 16, Folder 557)
    - Wright, C. Hayley, 1908 December 5 (Box 16, Folder 558)
    - Yale University, 1921 April 2 (Box 16, Folder 559)
      Letter to Anson Phelps Stokes, secretary of the university, declining the offer of an honorary degree.
      Deposited by the Office of the Secretary, April 26, 1935.
    - Unidentified
      Letters written by Barrie to unidentified recipients; many are addressed to "Dear Sir" or "Dear Madam." Letters bearing salutations with any part of a name (such as "Miss Wooten," "Lady Simson," or "Stephen") were filed alphabetically under the name in the preceding boxes.
      - Draft written as chairman of the Royal Literary Fund, 1930 March 14 (Box 16, Folder 560)
        Extending an invitation to the 140th dinner of the Royal Literary Fund.
      - Letter enclosing clipping announcing Barrie's marriage to Mary Ansell, undated (Box 16, Folder 561)
        Newspaper clipping dated July 9, 1894.
      - Letter from "Simon" to "James", 1923 March 13 (Box 16, Folder 562)
        Autograph letter written in a disguised hand
      - Three letters, 1902–1903 (Box 16, Folder 563)
        Published in the Letters of J. M. Barrie, edited by Viola Meynell (New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1947).
      - Sixty-one letters, 1888–1921 (Box 16, Folder 564-565)
      - Fragments, envelopes, and clipped autographs, 1899; undated (Box 16, Folder 566)
  - Letters to J. M. Barrie
    Arranged alphabetically by author.
    - Adams, Maude, 1915–1928 (Box 16, Folder 567)
    - Archer, William, 1907 October 18 (Box 16, Folder 568)
      Concerning government censorship of dramatic productions.
    - Baldwin, Stanley Baldwin, Earl, 1928–1936 (Box 16, Folder 569)
    - Barrie, Margaret Ogilvy, circa 1892 (Box 16, Folder 570)
      Accompanied by an envelope with a note in the hand of Lady Cynthia Asquith: "Letter from Margaret Ogilvie." Published in Letters of J. M. Barrie, edited by Viola Meynell (New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1947).
    - Birrell, Augustine, 1902; 1903 (Box 16, Folder 571)
      Containing references to cricket and to Barrie's The Little White Bird. A note by Eleanor Birrell was written across the top of the November letter.
    - Buchan, John, 1932 April 26 (Box 16, Folder 572)
    - "Cecil", 1932 April 26 (Box 16, Folder 573)
    - Chamberlain, Neville, 1932 April 27 (Box 16, Folder 574)
    - Clemens, Samuel Langhorne: calling card, signed, undated (Box 16, Folder 575)
      Autograph manuscript note on card: "Merry Christmas, O dear and honored Peter Pan! Mark Twain."
    - Coleman, John, 1900 November 5 (Box 16, Folder 576)
      Concerning assistance for a colleague from the Literary Fund.
    - Davies, Michael Llewelyn, 1917 July 2 (Box 16, Folder 577)
    - Ford, Madox Ford, 1907 (Box 16, Folder 578)
    - Frohman, Charles, 1906; 1915 (Box 16, Folder 579)
      Letter offering Barrie a box at the Duke of York's Theatre, and cablegram to Panbar [cable address for Barrie] concerning the world rights for The Little Minister.
    - Galsworthy, John, 1907; 1916 (Box 16, Folder 580)
      Concerning government censorship of dramatic productions. Enclosure in 1907 letter: autograph letter, signed, to John Galsworthy from William Archer (October 11, 1907).
    - Gilmour, Thomas Lennox, 1915 June 15 (Box 16, Folder 581)
      Concerning government war loans.
    - Grey of Fallodon, Edward Grey, Viscount, 1932 April 28 (Box 17, Folder 582)
    - Grosmith, Weedon, undated (Box 17, Folder 583)
    - Hewlett, Maurice Henry, 1902; 1905 (Box 17, Folder 584)
      Letter of 1905 predicting that Peter Pan will become a classic.
    - Hutchinson, A. S. M. (Arthur Stuart-Menteth), 1921; 1922 (Box 17, Folder 585)
    - Kipling, Rudyard, 1928 November 12 (Box 17, Folder 586)
      Declining an invitation.
    - Lloyd George, David, 1932 April 26 (Box 17, Folder 587)
    - Lucas, E. V. (Edward Verrall), 1927 December 8 (Box 17, Folder 588)
    - Lyceum Theatre (manager), 1891 January 28 (Box 17, Folder 589)
    - MacDonald, James Ramsay, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 590)
    - Mackenzie, Compton, 1922 January 4 (Box 17, Folder 591)
    - Millar, Hubert Stanhope, 1903 February 3 (Box 17, Folder 592)
    - Moore, George, undated (Box 17, Folder 593)
    - Munro, Neil, 1930 July 16 (Box 17, Folder 594)
    - Murray, Gilbert, 1907–1932 (Box 17, Folder 595)
      Letter of 1907 concerns government censorship of dramatic productions.
    - Priestley, J. B. (John Boynton), 1930 September 24 (Box 17, Folder 596)
    - Salisbury, James Edward Hubert Gascoyne-Cecil, Marquess of, 1932 April 26 (Box 17, Folder 597)
    - Samuel, Herbert Louis Samuel, Viscount, 1932 April 25 (Box 17, Folder 598)
    - The Scotsman, 1891 September 30 (Box 17, Folder 599)
      Enclosure wanting: bank check for £15/15 in payment for Barrie's contribution as "Grenville" to The Scotsman 's London Letter column. Printed form letter; on verso is a list of the articles and dates of publication for which payment was made.
    - Shaw, Bernard, 1924 September 30 (Box 17, Folder 600)
    - Simon, John Allsebrook Simon, Viscount, 1932 (Box 17, Folder 601)
    - Snowden, Philip Snowden, Viscount, 1932 April 25 (Box 17, Folder 602)
    - Swan, Annie S., 1930 May (Box 17, Folder 603)
    - Terry, Ellen, Dame, 1901 November 16 (Box 17, Folder 604)
      Incomplete (6 pages) letter containing references to Maude Adams as Phoebe Throssel in Barrie's play Quality Street.
    - Thomson, J. J. (Joseph John), 1930 (Box 17, Folder 605)
    - Walkley, Arthur Bingham, 1913 June 7 (Box 17, Folder 606)
    - Wells, H. G. (Herbert George), 1937 June 14 (Box 17, Folder 607)
    - Windsor, Edward, Duke of, 1929 April 18 (Box 17, Folder 608)
      Thanking Barrie for his gift of the rights to Peter Pan to the Great Ormond Street Hospital.
    - Unidentified, 1917–1932 (Box 17, Folder 609)
  - Charles Scribner's Sons Correspondence
    The subseries holds Charles Scribner's Sons corporate correspondence files concerning the publication of Barrie's works in the United States. It consists of more than 1,000 letters and copies of letters relating to publishing details, written by Barrie, staff at Charles Scribner's Sons and Hodder and Stoughton, and other correspondents, chiefly Lady Cynthia Asquith and Peter Llewelyn Davies after 1937. The letters contain references to Arnold Bennett, Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, John Galsworthy, Thomas Hardy, Sir Compton Mackenzie, John Masefield, George Meredith, William Lyon Phelps, Sir Arthur Quiller-Couch, George Bernard Shaw, Robert Louis Stevenson, Mary Webb, H. G. Wells, and other literary and theatrical personalities.
    - Index to folder contents, undated (Box 18, Folder 610)
      Typed list of letters appearing in the folders following, including list of topics covered in each folder. A carbon copy of each sheet appears in the relevant folder.
    - Index to Scribner's letter book, undated (Box 18, Folder 611)
      Manuscript index (in an unidentified hand) to an 1891-1909 letter book probably kept in the files of Charles Scribner's Sons, giving the date and a précis of letters sent between Barrie and Charles Scribner, Edward L. Burlingame, and Lemuel W. Bangs.
    - Correspondence, 1891–1927 (Box 18, Folder 612-627)
    - Correspondence, 1928–1945 (Box 19, Folder 628-640)
  - Third-Party Letters About J. M. Barrie
    The subseries holds letters written by Barrie's friends and colleagues that discuss Barrie or his work.
    Arranged alphabetically by sender.
    - Ansell, Mary
      - to H. C. Marillier, 1905? (Box 20, Folder 641)
      - to Bernard Partridge, undated (Box 20, Folder 642)
        Declining an invitation issued to Barrie and Mary Ansell.
      - to Charles Scribner, undated (Box 20, Folder 643)
        Issuing an invitation to lunch with Barrie and Mary Ansell.
      - ALS to [Austin?] Strong, 1907 August 18 (Box 20, Folder 644)
    - Asquith, Cynthia, Lady
      - to William Lewin, 1936 August 13 (Box 20, Folder 645)
        Concerning Barrie's early career in journalism in Nottingham and London, and with references to "Caught Napping"; signed "C. Greene."
      - to Hilda Trevelyan, 1955 December 14 (Box 20, Folder 646)